以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的，所以这是重要的一天
ok so this is an important day and
星期五是重要的一天，希望你
Friday was an important day I I hope you
享受教授的Fras太棒了
enjoyed professor's Fras terrific
演讲，就像我做你可能
lecture as much as I did you probably
看见我记笔记疯狂的
saw me taking notes like mad for the
要写入有关节现在
section that's now to be written about
随机梯度下降所以他和他
stochastic gradient descent so and he he
如果你记得并且答应了一个定理
promised a theorem if you remember and
没有时间，所以他要去
there wasn't time and so he was going to
发送给我或仍然要发送
send it to me or still is going to send
对我来说，我会报告我没有得到它
it to me I'll report I haven't got it
但我会这样，但我会把它带到课堂上
yet so I'll but I'll bring it to class
等待和希望看到和那个
wait and see hopefully about and that'll
让我们有机会回顾随机性
give us a chance to review stochastic
梯度下降中心算法
gradient descent the central algorithm
深度学习然后今天就是这样
of deep learning and then this today is
关于深层的中心结构
about the central structure of deep
神经网和你们中的一些人会知道
neural nets and some of you will know
已经是他们如何联系的了
already what they how they're connected
什么是什么功能f
what what the what the function f the
学习功能它可以把它叫做
learning function it could call it the
那是学习功能
learning function that that's
构建了整个系统的目标
constructed the whole system is aiming
在构建这个函数f
at constructing this function f which
然后学习训练数据
learns the training data and then
将它应用于测试数据和
applying it to the test data and the
奇迹是它在这方面做得很好
miracle is that it does so well in in
实践那就是改变了
practice that's what has transformed
深入学习如此重要
deep learning into such a important
应用程序，以便使，所以这是
application so so so this is
这虽然第七章已经开始了
this though Chapter seven has been up
几个月来吉祥物mit.edu斜线
for months on the mascot mit.edu slash
从数据视觉中学习，我会添加它
learning from data sight and I'll add it
太棒了，因为那就是你要去的地方
to stellar because that's where you'll
正在寻找它好然后
be looking for it okay and then the
第二个反向传播的方式
second the backpropagation the way to
我可能会计算梯度
compute the gradient I'll probably
今天达到了这个想法，你会看到
reached that idea today and you'll see
什么是连锁规则，但它是怎么回事
what it's the chain rule but how is it
组织好，所以这是什么
organized okay so so what's the
结构是什么样的深层计划
structure what's the plan for deep
神经网络从这里开始就是好的开始
neural nets good start starting here so
我们所拥有的是培训数据，所以我们拥有
what we have is training data so we have
向量x1到X我应该使用什么
vectors x1 to X what should I use for
那些样本的培训数量
the number of training of samples that
我们在训练中接受了培训
we have in the training the training
数据好Sadie数据确定和每个
data well Sadie for data ok and each
矢量那些被称为特征向量
vector those are called feature vectors
所以每个都等于特征向量
so equals feature vectors so each one
每个X都是呃有这样的特征
each X is uh has like m features so
也许它可能是我的符号不是
maybe it maybe I my notation isms isn't
这里很热，我有很多
so hot here I have a whole lot of
向量让我不要使用下标
vectors let me not use the subscript for
那些正确的矢量功能
those right away so vectors feature
向量和每个向量可能都有
vectors and each vector has got maybe so
我们说m的功能就像我们一样
we say m features like if we were
测量身高，年龄和体重
measuring height and age and weight and
所以这些工作就是特色
so on those would be features so the job
是神经网络的工作
is of the the job of the neural network
是创造一个和
is to create a and
我们打算也许我们分类
and we're going to classify maybe we're
要对男女老少进行分类
going to classify men and women or boys
和女孩
and girls
所以我们让它成为一个分类
so our let's make it a classification
问题只是一个二进制所以
problem a just a binary so the
分类问题是我们应该做的
classification problem is what should we
说减去一个或一个或类似的
say minus one or one which is sort of or
零或一个或男孩或女孩或猫或狗
zero or one or boy or girl or cat or dog
或卡车或汽车或反正只有两个
or truck or car or anyway just two
课程到两个班，所以我要去
classes to two class so I'm just gonna
做两级分类所以我们
do two class classification so the we
知道训练数据属于哪个类
know which class the training data is in
对于每个向量X，我们知道正确的
for each vector X we know the right
回答所以我们要创建一个函数
answer so we want to create a function
给出正确的答案，然后
that gives the right answer and then
我们将在其他数据上使用该功能
we'll use that function on other data
人们都知道，所以让我写下来
people know so let me write that down
创建一个X的函数f，以便
create a function f of X that so that
获得大部分的课程都是正确的
that gets most of gets the class correct
换句话说，X的f应该是负数
in other words f of X should be negative
当分类是什么时候
for when when the classification is
X的减1和f应为正
minus 1 and f of X should be positive
当分类加1和as时
when the classification is plus 1 and as
我们知道我们不一定得到
we know we don't necessarily have to get
每X个样品都可能正确
every X every sample right that may be
如果有一些样品过度拟合
overfitting if there's some sample
得到那个真的很奇怪
that's just truly weird by getting that
我们正在寻找
right we're going to be looking for
测试集中的真正奇怪的数据和
truly weird data in the test set and and
这不是我们想要的，我们希望有一个好主意
that's not a good idea we want we want
我们试图发现的规则
the rule that we're trying to discover
该规则的
the rule the
涵盖几乎所有情况，但不是每个
covers almost all cases but not every
疯狂怪异的情况好吧这是我们的工作
crazy weird case okay so that's our job
创建一个X的函数f
to create a function f of X that is
几乎所有的训练都是正确的
correct on almost all of the training
数据是的
data yeah
所以之前我画的图片
so before I draw the picture of the
网络让我记得记住
network let me just remember remember to
提到我不知道的网站游乐场
mention the site playground I don't know
如果你已经看过那么我会
if you've looked at that so I'm gonna
问你在tensorflowdotorg的游乐场
ask you playground at tensorflow dot org
有多少人知道该网站或已经搞砸了
how many know that site or have messed
只有几个没关系好吧
with it just just a few okay okay so
它不是一个非常复杂的网站
it's not a very sophisticated site it's
只有四个例子和例子
got only four examples for examples and
是的，所以这样一个例子是一个
and the yeah so the so one example is a
很多积分都有蓝色B表示
whole lot of points there are blue B for
蓝色里面有一堆点
blue inside a bunch of points that are
另一套旧的橙色
another set that are old for orange
橙色，但没关系，所以这两个
orange but okay so those are the two
类橙色和蓝色所以点X.
classes orange and blue so the points X
并且特征向量是
and the the feature vector is is the
特征向量在这里只是X.
feature vector is here is just the X
坐标的特征是X.
what the coordinates features are the X
点的Y坐标和我们的工作
Y coordinates of the point and our job
是找到一个积极的功能
is to find a function that's positive on
这些点和负面的
these points and negative on those
分那么有一个简单的模型问题
points so there's a simple model problem
和
and
我建议也只是部分是，如果
I recommend well just partly it's if
你是深度学习的专家
you're a expert in deep learning this is
对于孩子，但在道德上我在这里
for children but but morally here I
当然在玩这个教训
certainly learned from playing in this
操场上，所以你设置了你，你
playground so you you set the you you
设置步长您设置还是设置
set the step size do you set it or does
它说没有，是的，我想你可以
it say no yeah yeah I guess you can
改变它我没有我不认为我
change it I haven't I don't think I've
改变它你还说什么哦你
changed it what else do you said oh you
你设置了非线性激活
you set the the nonlinear activation the
非线性激活函数有效
nonlinear activation function active
我会说功能，让我走吧
I'll say function and let me just go
在这里，说什么功能的人
over here and say what functions people
现在大多使用激活
now mostly use the the activation
函数被称为riilu发音
function is called riilu pronounced
不同的方式我不知道我们得到了什么
different ways I don't know how we got
进入这个功能的疯狂的事情
into that crazy thing for this function
这是零和X所以函数riilu
that is zero and X so the function riilu
作为X的函数是最大的
as a function of X is the maximum the
大于0和X所以它产生了
larger of 0 and X so it produces the
要点是它不是线性的和重点
point is it's not linear and the point
如果我们不允许非线性
is that if we didn't allow non-linearity
在这里的某个地方
in here somewhere
我们甚至无法解决这个游乐场
we couldn't even solve this playground
问题因为如果我们的分类器是
problem because if our classifiers were
所有线性分类器，如支持
all linear classifiers like support
矢量机我无法分开
vector machines I couldn't separate the
蓝色的橙色与飞机我是
blue from the orange with a plane I it's
以某种方式创造了一些非线性
got to somehow create some nonlinear
函数可能是函数
function which is maybe the function is
努力成为一个好的功能
trying to be a good a good function
可能是r和theta的函数
would be a function of r and theta maybe
也许r减5所以也许是距离
maybe r minus 5 so maybe the distance
那个让我们假设的那个
out to the that let's suppose that
距离是5然后r减5
distance is 5 then r minus 5 will be
对蓝调不利，因为R很小
negative on the Blues because R is small
我们的负5将是正面的
and our minus 5 will be positive on the
橘子因为R更大而且
oranges because R is bigger and
因此我们会有正确的迹象
therefore we will have the right signs
小于0大于0，它会
less than 0 greater than 0 and it'll
将此数据归类为此
classify this the this data this
训练数据是的，所以它必须这样做
training data yeah so so it has to do
这不是一件难事
that this is not a hard one to do there
我说两个是四个例子
are four examples as I say two are
琐事它解决了它找到了一个好处
trivial it solves it finds a good
功能很好是啊我忘记了
function well yeah I've forgotten
他们是如此微不足道，他们却没有
they're so trivial they've they don't
不应该提及然后这是
shouldn't be mentioned and then this is
中等测试然后硬测试
the medium test and then the hard test
当你有橘子时，你有一种
is when you have oranges you have a sort
橙子螺旋和里面你有
of spiral of oranges and inside you have
一个煮熟的蓝色缎面螺旋
a spiral of blue satin that was a cooked
同比饲料，所以你会这么说的
up by a feed so you would so that the
系统正试图找到一个功能
system is trying to find a function
这在一个螺旋上是正面的
that's positive on one spiral and
另一方面也是负面的
negative on the other spiral and that
需要相当多的时间
takes quite a bit of time many many
时代我学会了一个时代
epochs I learned what an epoch is did
你知道什么是一个时代，我没有
you know what an epoch is I I didn't
知道是不是只是一个花哨的词
know whether it was just a fancy word
用于计算渐变中的步数
for counting the steps in gradient
血统，但它计算它的数量
descent but it counts it counts the
步骤可以，但一个时代就是
steps all right but one epoch is the
与大小匹配的步数
number of steps that matches the size of
训练数据，如果你有一个
the training data so if you have a
百万个样本我们正在评分普通
million samples we're grading ordinary
渐渐下降你会做一个
gradient descent you would be doing a
百万你有一百万
million you have a million by
当然随机的每一步问题
in problem per step of course stochastic
梯度下降只做一个小批量
gradient descent just does a mini batch
1或32或者其他什么，但无论如何，如果我们
of 1 or 32 or something but anyway if we
是的，所以这是你的数量
had yeah so so it's the number of you
必须做足够的迷你批次
have to do enough mini batches so that
你所涵盖的总数是
the total number you've covered is the
相当于一个完整的通过
equivalent of one full run through the
训练数据，这很有趣
training data and that was interesting
点没有你在拿起点
point did you pick up that point that in
随机梯度下降你可以
stochastic gradient descent you could
或者你可以做迷你
either do it you could either do a mini
批量然后将它们放回汤中
batch and then put them back in the soup
因此与更换或者你可以只
so with replacement or you could just
从奇迹中提取数据
put your data in some order from wonder
zillion所以这里是第一个X.
zillion so here's here's of a first X
然后更多的X，然后只是和
and then more more X's and then just and
随机化订单，所以你必须
randomize the order so you'd have to
随机化顺序为随机
randomize the order for for stochastic
梯度下降是合理的
gradient descent to be reasonable and
然后拿一个小批量和迷你
then take a mini batch and the mini
在迷你批次中批量批量生产
batch in a mini batch in a mini batch
当你到达底部时，你已经到了
and when you get to the bottom you've
完成了一个时代，然后你就完成了
finished one epoch and then you'd
也许如果你可能再次随机
probably randomize again maybe if you
如果你愿意的话，如果你这样做的话
were if you were doing it if you wanted
过着正确的生活并经历迷你
to live right and go through the mini
再批次，可能做一千
batches again and probably do a thousand
无论如何，所以我还没说
times yeah anyway so I haven't said yet
你做了什么X的这个是什么样的但是
what you do what this f of X is like but
你可以在屏幕上看到它
you can sort of see it on the screen
因为它创造了这个功能
because as it creates this function f it
有点情节和你在上面看到的
kind of plots it and what you see on the
屏幕是为此设置的零
screen is the is the zero set for that
功能，所以它是完美的
function so it perfect would be for it
如果我有另一个，那就去零
to go through zero if I had another
颜色哦，我有另一个
color oh I do have another
看这是第一次整体
look this is the first time the whole
学期蓝色已经出现好了所以如果
semester blue has appeared okay so so if
如果该功能在那里是积极的
it if the function was positive there in
在这部分关于蓝调和
the in this part on the Blues and
在该地区以外的负面
negative outside that region for the
橙子，这正是我们想要的
oranges that would be just what we want
对
right
那就是这个小小的东西
that would be what this little
游乐场网站正在创建和上
playground site is creating and on the
屏幕你会看到它你会看到这个
screen you'll see it you'll see this
这条曲线，它穿过零，以便
this curve where it crosses zero so that
假设它穿过零的曲线
curve where it crosses zero is supposed
分开两套一套是
to separate the two sets one set is
积极的一套是负面的
positive one set is negative where it's
零介于两者之间，重点在于它
zero is in between and the point is it's
不是直线，因为我们有
not a straight line because we've got
这个非线性函数就是这个
this nonlinear function this this this
是非线性的，它允许我们拥有
is nonlinear and it allows us to to have
功能就像我们的减五等等
functions like our minus five and so at
五点那就是功能所在
at five that's where the function would
是零，你会看到，在
be zero and that you'll see that on the
屏幕你可能只是去帐篷或
screen you might just go to tents or
当然，在tensorflow的游乐场
playground at tensorflow of course
tensorflow是一个很大很大的系统，这是
tensorflow is a big big system this is
他们孩子的部门但是我
the their child's department but it's I
以为它很不错然后继续
thought it was pretty good and then on
这个网站你决定了多少层
this site you you decide how many layers
每个神经元中会有多少神经元
there will be how many neurons in each
图层，以便您创建结构
layer so you create the structure that
我即将画画，你不会
I'm about to draw and and you won't be
能够解决这两个问题
able to get to solve this two problem to
找到一个学习该数据的函数f
find a function f that learns that data
没有多少层和一个数字
without a number of layers and a number
如果你不给它足够的神经元
of neurons if you don't give it enough
你会看到它挣扎但它不会
you'll see it struggling but it won't it
只是它创造了零集
just it's creating that the the zero set
试图遵循这一点，但它有它
tries to follow this but it but it has
它在某个时候放弃了
it gives up at some point
这个不需要太多层次
this one doesn't take too many layers
而这两个琐碎的例子就是
and the two trivial examples just are
只有少数神经元可以正常工作
just a few neurons do the job okay so
现在对一个人进行一点评论
now so that's a little comment on on one
网站，如果你知道其他人的父亲
website if others father if you know
我应该知道的其他网站
other websites that I should know and
应该引起注意你能发送吗？
should call attention to could you send
我发了一封电子邮件我知道我不是
me an email I you know I'm just not
知道一切，但在那里或如果
aware of everything but out there or if
你知道一个好的卷积
you know a good a good convolutional
神经网络CNN可用于
neural net CNN that is available to
练习你可以给它的地方
practice on where you could give it the
训练设置就是我在说什么
training set that's what I'm talking
在这里，我很高兴知道，因为我
about here I'd be glad to know because I
我只是不知道这一切
I just don't know all that
我应该没问题，那是什么呢
that I should okay so what does the
功能看起来和我说的一样线性
function look like well as I say linear
不会这样做，但线性是一个
isn't going to do it but linear is a
它的很重要的一部分的这
very important part of it of the of this
函数f所以函数f确实有
function f so the function f really has
形式很好，所以我们从这里开始
the form well so we've got we start here
用一个二三三四的矢量是
with a vector of one two three four M is
五是这是矢量X.
five this is the this is the vector X
五个组件好吧让我擦除
five components okay so let me erase
现在好吗
that now okay
那么我们就有了第一层
so then we have layer one with some
分数让我们说N一个是六
number of points let's say N one is six
神经元让我这个简单的我会
neurons let me make this simple I'll
只是有一个层，然后我会
just have that one layer and then I'll
有输出这将是输出
have the output this will be the output
层
layer
它只是一个数字所以
and it's just gonna be one number so
每一个所以我会有一个矩阵
each of these so I'm gonna have a matrix
一个让我从这一个人的意志
a one that takes me from this a one will
这将是5乘5乘5
be this will be 5 by no six by five
因为我想要六个输出和五个输出
because I want six outputs and five
输入六乘五矩阵，所以我有30
inputs six by five matrix so I have 30
在那里选择权重等等
weights to choose there and so the the
所散发出来的y是要为y1
the y that comes out is gonna be y 1
将是X0的1倍，因此X0是
will be a 1 times X 0 so X 0 is the is
具有五个组件的特征向量
the feature vector with five components
所以它是一个纯线性的东西
so it's so that's a purely linear thing
但我们也想要一个偏移函数
but we also want a an offset function
偏移向量所以这是一个载体，这是
offset vector so that's a vector this is
然后这就是即将到来的
then this is that was a y that's coming
out有六个组件，一个是六个组件
out has six components the a one is six
由五个X化为乌有是五经之一，
by five the X naught was five by one and
那么当然这是六经之一，所以
then of course this is six by one so
这些都是权重
these are the these are the weights well
这些都是这些我会称之为全部
these are these yeah I'll call them all
这样计算重量的权重
weight weights to compute so in this so
这些都是通常连接的图片
these are connected usual picture is to
展示这些所有这些联系我会
show these all these connections I'll
只是把它们中的一些放在这里我们
just put in some of them so in here we
有三十六个参数
have thirty plus six parameters
三十六个参数然后我要去
thirty-six parameters and then I'm going
关闭这将是一个非常
to close this it's gonna be a very
浅薄的东西，这将只是公正
shallow thing so that will be just just
一点一点，是的，没关系
one by six yeah just okay
对，所以我们只得到一个输出
right so we're just getting one output
所以这只是一个向量
so it's that's just a vector at this
最后一点，但当然是整体
final point but of course the the whole
深度神经网络的想法就是你
idea of deep neural Nets is that you
有很多层，所以你有36个
have many layers so you have that 36
更现实，就像数十个
more realistically as in the tens of
成千上万，你有多次
thousands and you have it multiple times
而这个想法似乎是第一个
and the idea seems to be that the first
你可以分类的那个层
layer that you can sort of separate what
第一层了解数据和来自
layer one learns about the data and from
第二层了解数据
what layer two learns about the data
层有一个由是一个明显
layer one there's a one apparently by
只是照顾这个计算
just looking after the computation this
了解了一些有关的基本事实
learned some some basic facts about the
这将学习下一个a到的数据
data this learns the next next a to
会在这里进一步了解更多
which would go in here would learn more
细节然后三个会学到更多
detail and then a three would learn more
细节，所以我们会有一些
details so we would have a number of
层和它的构造
layers and it's that construction that
已经使神经网络成功但我
has made neural net successful but I
还没完，因为现在是
haven't finished because right now it's
我现在只有线性的
only linear right now I just have
现在我在这里喝两杯酒
alcohol at a two in here right now I
只会有一个矩阵乘法
would just have a matrix multiplication
应用1然后应用2但是在
apply a 1 and then apply a 2 but in
之间是一个一个接一个的动作
between there's a is a one by one action
在这个功能上
on each by this function
以便该函数对该数字起作用
so that function acts on that number to
再给那个号码还是给
give that number back again or to give
零，所以在那里有真正的哦
zero so in in there in there is real ooh
就在那里，它变得真实
right in there in this it becomes real
哦，每六个六个副本的反应
ooh on each six six copies of reacting
这六个数字中的每一个都是正确的
on each of those six numbers right
所以真正的x1来自于y1
so that really x1 comes from y1 by
将riilu应用于它然后给予它
applying riilu to it then that gives the
X所以这里是线性的Y.
X so here are the Y's from the linear
一部分，这里有这就是为什么那些在X
part and here are the X that's why ones
这是一个矢量y1，线性来自于
that's a vector y1 the linear from just
线性加一个仿射图线性加
a linear plus an affine map linear plus
不变
constant
这很好，然后下一步是
that's a fine and then the next step is
逐个组件我们应用它
component by component we apply this
功能，我们得到X-X是什么和
function and we get X - X what yeah and
然后再一次又一次这样做
then do it again and again and again so
你看到我的功能如何？
do you see that the function how do i
现在描述x的函数f所以
describe now the function f of x so the
学习功能依赖于
learning function which depends on the
关于a和b的权重是如此
on the weights on the a's and b's is so
我从XI开始申请F1a1
I start with an X I apply F 1 a 1 to it
是的，让我这样做，这是什么
yeah let me do this so what what this is
函数fX的XF的打算
the function f of X f of X is going to
是F3，假设是X12的F1的F2
be F 3 let's say of F 2 of F 1 of X 1 2
3个括号没错，所以这是一个链条
3 parentheses right okay so it's a chain
你可以说F是正确的
you could say F is a what's the right
如果我采取一系列功能的话
word for a chain of functions if I take
函数的函数是
a function of a function which is the
我使用单词链的原因
reason I use the word chain
链规则给出了导数
the chain rule gives the derivative so a
一个函数的函数功能
function of a function of a function
这就是所谓的作曲创作
that's called composition composing
功能所以这是一个作文我
function so this is a composition I
不知道是否有标准符号
don't know if there's a standard symbol
从F1开始并做一些
for starting with F 1 and do some
组成和做一些组成和
composition and do some composition and
那些什么是那些单独的F那些
now what what are those separate F those
单独的FS是或者那样的
separate FS are the or the so the
单独的FS是向量的F1
separate FS are the F 1 of a vector
将调整真实的部分
would be in tunes the real part the
非线性部分1X0加B1所以2
nonlinear part of a 1 X 0 plus B 1 so 2
部分你做线性或仿射地图
parts you do the linear or affine map on
你的特征向量，然后你
your feature vector and then you
您应用该组件的组件
component by component you apply that
非线性函数，它需要一些
nonlinear function and it took some
年中非线性函数之前
years before that nonlinear function
成为人们想象的最爱
became a big favorite people imagine
这对我来说更重要
that it was better it was important to
原来有顺畅的功能
have a smooth function so the original
功能是sigmoids
functions were sigmoids
喜欢s曲线，但当然它
like s curves but but of course it
原来，试验表明，
turned out that experiment showed that
这样做的效果更好是的
this worked even better yes so that
将是F1然后F2将具有
would be F 1 and then F 2 would have the
相同的形式和F3将具有相同的形式
same form and F 3 would have the same
因此，这可能有36个重量和
form so maybe this had 36 weights and
下一个会有另一个号码
the next one would have another number
和下一个号码所以我们是
and the next another number so we're
让你变得相当复杂
getting you get quite complicated
你知道，由作曲组成的功能
functions by composition by you know
喜欢X的正弦或正弦的正弦
like e to the sine of X or e to the sine
X的对数或类似的东西
of the logarithm of X or things like
那
that
纯粹的群众问你能得到什么
pure masses asked could you get what
功能可以让你知道尝试
functions can you get you know try to
现在想起他们都是什么样的
think of them all now what kind of
功能我们在这里有什么可以说的
functions do we have here what can I say
关于X的f作为数学函数
about f of X as a function as a math
人是什么样的功能
person what what kind of a function is
因此它是由矩阵和
it so it's created out of matrices and
线性或仿射图中的向量
vectors out of a linear or affine map
然后是非线性的
followed by a nonlinear by that
特别是非线性函数那么
particular nonlinear function so what
我有一种功能
kind of a function is it well I've
虽然写下了这些话
written though with those words down up
这里在X的f将是一个
here at f of X is going to be a
连续分段线性函数
continuous piecewise linear function
因为每一步都是连续的
because every step is continuous that's
连续函数线性函数
a continuous function linear functions
是连续的功能所以我们当然
are continuous function so we certainly
有我们正在做的一个组成
have we're taking a composition of
连续功能，所以它是连续的
continuous function so it's continuous
部分是线性的
and it's piecewise linear because part
它是线性的，部分是线性的
of it is linear and part of it is
分段线性所以这是一些
piecewise linear so so this is some
连续分段线性函数
continuous piecewise linear function
来自XX和M的功能
function from from of X X and M
尺寸没关系
dimensions okay
所以我有一个小小的数学问题
so one one little math question which I
认为有助于向迈克理解
think helps to understand to Mike like
吞下一连串的想法
to swallow the idea of a chain of of the
我们在这里有一种线性链
kind of chain we have here of linear
其次是riilu所以这就是我的
followed by riilu so so here's my
问题这是一个问题，我要
question this is a question I'm going to
问
ask
顺便说一句，回传就是
and by the way back propagation is
当Z相当肯定会来
certainly going to come when Z rather
比今天这是一个重要话题
than today that's a major topic in
本身让我继续这个
itself so let me keep going with this
功能你可以得到任何功能
function could you get any function
无论如何这种方式你都不会得到
whatsoever this way well no you only get
连续分段线性函数
continuous piecewise linear functions
这是一个有趣的案例让我
that's a it's an interesting case let me
只是问你一个练习
just ask you well one of the exercises
如果我连续两次，我会说
says if if I took two continuous
分段线性函数你有吗？
piecewise linear functions do you have a
接下来的20分钟是企图
the next 20 minutes are an attempt to
给我们的图形的图片
give us a picture of the graph of a
分段线性函数那么什么
piecewise linear function so what what
比如说两个变量的函数
say in say a function of two variables
所以我的M等于2，我画了它
so I have M equal to two and I draw its
graph好帮我画出它的图表
graph okay help me to draw its graph so
这将是f1x1x2和f的图形
this would be a graph of f of x1 x2 and
它将是连续的
it's going to be continuous and
分段线性所以它的图形是什么
piecewise linear so what does its graph
看起来就是那个问题
look like that's that's the question
什么是分段的图表呢？
what's the graph of a piecewise then
你的功能看起来很好
your function looks like well it's got
变化之间的扁平碎片
flat pieces right in between the change
从美杜莎分段，这意味着它
from a Medusa piecewise that means it's
得到不同的东西，但在一块之内
got different pieces but within a piece
它是线性的，旁边的部分适合
it's linear and the pieces fit next to
因为它是相互适应的
fit with each other because it's
连续所以我视觉上
continuous so I visually
这就是折纸这就好了
is that the well it's like origami this
折纸理论几乎是正确的
is the theory of origami almost so right
折纸，你拿一个扁平的东西和你
origami you take a flat thing and you
沿着直的折叠折叠它所以
fold it along straight folds so so
与折纸有什么不同可能不是
what's different from origami maybe not
许多
much
也许折纸允许比我们更多
well maybe origami allows more than we
允许你在这里折纸
allow here origami would allow you to
将它折叠起来然后折纸就可以了
fold it up and over so origami would
因为你，给你一个多值的东西
give you a multivalued thing because you
知道它有一个顶部和底部和
know it's got a top and a bottom and
其他折叠，这只是出去
other folds this is just going out to
扁平的无限和问题
infinity in flat pieces and the question
将会有多少件让我问
will be how many pieces so let me ask
你这个问题我有多少件
you that question how many pieces do I
你知道我的意思吗？
have you see what I mean by a piece so
所以我想，有一个图表
so I'm thinking of a graph that has
这些扁平的碎片和它们相连
these flat pieces and they're connected
沿直的直边和那些
along straight straight edges and those
直边来从实际
straight edges come from from the real
操作得好，有两个
ooh operation that well that's got two
实际上我们可以在一天内完成
pieces actually we could do in one day
有一天我们可以数一数
and one day we could count the number of
件很容易，所以会是什么
pieces pretty easily so what would what
将是一个分段线性让我放
would be a piecewise linear let me put
它在这里的这一边，并删除它-
it over here on this side and erase it -
好的
okay
所以这里的枫树是连续的
so here's a maple one a continuous
分段线性
piecewise linear
我只是绘制它的图表就好了
f I'll just draw its graph so okay so
它是直件直件
it's got straight pieces straight pieces
就像这样，是的，你知道它是一个
like so yeah you've got the idea it's a
有时人们说破线型
broken line type sometimes people say
虚线，但我不确定
broken line but that I'm never sure
这是一个很好的说明
that's a good description of this
分段线性连续所以它是
piecewise linear continuous so it's
连续因为这些碎片相遇而且
continuous because the pieces meet and
它的分段线性显然是可以的
it's piecewise linear obviously okay so
这就是我所拥有的那种画面
that's the kind of picture I have for a
现在我的一个变量的功能
function of one variable now that my
问题是一种帮助尝试
question is as an aid to try to
在2d中可视化这个功能就是看
visualize this function in 2d is to see
如果我们可以计算这些碎片，看看我们是否可以
if we can count the pieces see if we can
算上件是和该
count the pieces yes and that for that
所以我在这个笔记中找到了它
so that's in this notes I found it in a
五位作者的论文来自于
paper by five authors for a from for a
会议和所以实际上整个世界
meeting and so actually the whole world
神经网络就是会议
of neural nets it's it's the conferences
每隔几年是那
every couple of years that that
每个人都准备提交超过
everybody prepares for submits more than
一张纸，所以它是一种分段的
one paper so it's kind of a piecewise
线性会议，而这些都是在
linear conference and those are the the
大型会议没关系，所以这就是后面
big conferences okay so this is the back
传播部分，我想看看
propagation section and I want to look
在这好吧所以我要表现出来
at this at the okay so I'm gonna show
Kleinberg和其他人的这篇论文
this paper by Kleinberg and for others
克莱因伯格是一个计算机科学专业的学生
Kleinberg is a he's a computer science
指导康奈尔，他是这里的博士
guide Cornell he was a PhD from here in
数学，他是一个非常
math and he's a very
并且重要的人不是这样
and significant person on not on not so
很多神经网络就像
much on neural networks as just the
整个计算机的整个部分
whole this whole part of computer
科学是正确的，无论如何他们和其他
science right so anyway they and other
人们都问这个同样的
people to have have asked this same
问题假设你认为我在
problem suppose you have suppose I'm in
两个变量，假设是什么
two variables and suppose so what are
你现在想象的是表面的
you imagining now for the surface of the
X的f和它的原因图
graph of this of f of X and why it has
这些线条折叠线
these it has these lines fold lines
好吧，我想它有折叠线，使
right I'm thinking it has fold lines so
我开始可以从一个完整的开始
I start could start with a complete
飞机和我沿着一条线折叠
plane and I fold it along along one line
所以现在就像RayLu是一个半场比赛
so now it's like Ray Lu is one play half
飞机他们要去另一半
plane they're going to a different half
每个人都带着它飞行，现在我
plane there everybody with it and now I
采取表面哪个功能
take that function that surface which
只有两部分，我放入另一部分
just has two parts and I put in another
折
fold
好吧，我现在有多少部分
okay how many parts have I got now I
我认为四点是正确的四个部分是的
think four am i right four parts yes
因为这与此不同
because this will be different from this
因为它沿着那条线折叠了
because it was folded along that line so
这些将是他们的四个不同的部分
these will be four different pieces they
它们在中心具有相同的价值
they have the same value at the center
在那里和他们匹配沿着
there and this and they match along the
线条，但有平坦的数量
lines but there's so the number of flat
这件事是四件，所以这就是
pieces is four for this so that's with
两折，现在我只想问你
two folds and now I just want to ask you
M折叠有多少件
with M folds how many pieces are there
我可以达到三倍，所以我会
can I get up to three folds so I'm gonna
寻找褶皱的数量，以便让我
look for the number of folds so let me
让我用得到的符号也许[R
let me just use a get a notation maybe R
R为平坦件数的数
R is the number of number of flat pieces
而M是我的X维度
and M is the dimension of X in my
图片是2和n是多少
picture it's 2 and n is the number of
折叠让我再说一遍
folds so let me say it again
我坐飞机，我会折起来平面
I'm taking a plane I'll fold it plane
因为维度是2
because the dimension was 2
我会折叠它折叠n倍
I'll fold it fold it n times how many
件
pieces
这将是多少扁平件
how many flat pieces so this would be
这将是一个中心步骤
this would be a central step in
了解他们的功能有多接近
understanding how close their function
你知道你有什么自由
you know what freedom you have in the
例如，函数f可以吗？
function f for example can you
通过逼近任意连续函数
approximate any continuous function by
通过采取这些功能之一
one of these functions f by taking
足够的折叠似乎是答案
enough folds seems like the answer
应该是肯定的，这是肯定的
should be yes and it is yes so that's
对于纯粹的数学而言，这是一个很重要的
the that's one big for pure math that's
一个问题就是这一类
one question is the is this class of
功能普遍，所以普遍性
functions universal so the universality
定理就是说任何一个
theorem would be to say that any any
函数正弦X无论如何
function sine X whatever could be
近似尽可能接近一个
approximated as close as you like by one
这些家伙有足够的折叠和结束
of these guys with enough fold and over
在这里，我们有点做得更多
here we're kind of making it more
数字，我们将计算
numerical we're going to count the
件数，只是怎么看
number of pieces to just to see how
很快就会成长，所以会发生什么
quickly do they grow so what happens
在这里，所以我现在有四个折叠
here so I have four folds now this right
现在我有n等于我mm这里是两个
now I have n equal to I mm is two here
在这张照片中
in this in this picture
而我正试图绘制表面和
and I'm trying to draw the surface and
在这里，我接受了两个，我接受了
here I've put in two did I take in yeah
两折，现在我要去
two folds and now I'm gonna go up to
三折好吧让我折叠起来
three folds okay so let me fold it along
那条线我现在有多少件
that line how many pieces have I got now
让我们看看我能算出那些碎片吗？
let's see can I count those pieces is it
如果我这样做，那么什么是公式呢？
seven so what is a formula what if I do
另一个结果发生了什么，我们做了什么
another fold what happens what end we do
另一个文件夹是的，也许是的
another folder yeah yeah maybe that's
会是它这是一个很好的问题
gonna be it it's a kind of nice question
因为这是可视化的
because it is care to visualize this
事情还好，所以发生了多少怎么样
thing okay so what happened how many how
如果我投入，那些线路中的很多都会是
many of those lines will be if I put in
第四线多少呀多少新
a fourth line how many yeah how many new
折叠我是否创造了那种
folds do I create that's kind of the
问题，我假设第四
question and I'm assuming that fourth
线不经过任何的这些
line doesn't go through any of these
指出它处于一般位置
points it's sort of in general position
是的，所以我做了第四行
yeah so I put in a fourth line done it
那没关系，所以这里发生了什么
there it is okay so what happened here
有多少新人创造了多少
how many new ones did it create how many
新的创造了它让我做到了
new ones did it create let me make that
一个绿色因为我有所区别
one green because I'm distinguishing
这是那个在之后添加的人
that's the guy that's added after the
原来我们有七个我们有
original we had we had seven we had
七件，现在我们已经有了
seven pieces and now we now we've got
更多是7它不是一个
more was it seven it was wasn't it one
二三四有五六七但现在
two three four five six seven but now
我有多少件或有多少件
how many pieces have I got or how many
这样做了多少件呢
how many pieces that did this did this
新线创造了我们想要的东西
new line create that's what we want to
构建它使用递归
build it up use a recursion
这件新品有多少件
how many pieces did this new new
这条新线折叠创造了一条
well this new line folded created one
新作品中有一件新作品
new piece there right one new piece
那里有一件新作品
there one new piece there one new piece
那么有四件新作品还可以
there so there are four new pieces okay
是的，所以有一些公式是正确的
yes so there's some formula right that's
要告诉我们，现在会怎么样
gonna tell us that and now what would
下一个创造得很好我现在有了
the next one create well I've got now I
有一两三四行，所以现在我
have one two three four lines so now I'm
要通过第五行和那个
gonna put through a fifth line and that
我会创造出一大堆作品
will create a whole bunch of pieces I'm
失去了失去这一点的线索
losing that losing the thread of this
争论，但你是正确的，是的
argument but you're onto it right yeah
所以任何建议都没关系，是的
so any any suggestions yeah okay yes
那是对的，所以有一个
there that's right so there's a
我想知道的递归公式
recursion formula that I want to know
我从Kleinberg的论文中学到了这一点
and I learned it from Kleinberg paper
然后我们有一个补充
and then and then we have an addition to
这样递归将告诉我如何
do so the recursion will tell me how
每一个新的都会增加
much it goes up each with each new
功能，那么我们必须添加好了，
function and then we have to add okay so
递归公式让我写出来
the recursion formula let me write that
下
down
所以这是我们现在和我想要的
so this is our of and and M now I'd like
找到一个公式，它的数量
to find a formula for it's the number of
M中的扁平件具有M维
flat pieces in M with an M dimensional
表面很好，我们把他们当作两个人
surface well we're taking em to be two
和n折叠，让我们等于1
and n folds and let's just so an equal 1
23让我们写下来的内容
2 3 let's let's write down the what the
我们知道的数字如何
numbers we know with with one fold how
到目前为止，很多东西太好了
many pieces too good so far so good with
一个折有两块所以这
one fold there were two pieces so this
是计数R然后两次折叠
is the count R and then with two folds
我们有多少人已经超越了这一点
how many we've gone past that point so
我们能回来吗
can we get back
只有那两个是好的谢谢
to just those two was it for okay thanks
现在，当我把第三折怎么样
now when I put in that third fold how
我没有绿线
many did I have without the green line
然而七是七，当时
yet seven was it seven and when the
第四个窗口进去，绿色去了
fourth window went in that green went
有多少人我在这张照片变得如此
how many have I got in this picture so
问题是我有多少新人
the question is how many new ones did I
创造我想那样那条线
create I guess so that that that line
被切成那块的那块
got chopped into that piece that piece
那块那块四片为
that piece that piece four pieces for
新系列四件新品
the new line four pieces for the new
然后每一行都像
line and then each of those pieces like
添加了一个扁平的位，因为它
added added a flat bit because it that
从这里到这里分开这些
piece from here to here separated these
两个以前只是一件
two which were previously just one piece
他们跟着它做了一件平板
one flat piece they followed it on that
我把它折叠在一起我在那里折叠了
line I folded on this I folded there I
认为它上升了四到十一个
think it went up by four to eleven so
现在我们只需要猜一个公式，
now we just have to guess a formula that
给那些匹配那些数字和
gives those matches those numbers and
当然我们真的应该猜测一下
then of course we really should guess it
对于任何M和任何N，我会写下来
for any M and any N and I'll write down
他们发现它的公式就是它
the formula that they found it's it
每个都涉及二项式数
involves binomial numbers every
世界上的一切都涉及到
everything in the world involves
二项式数，因为它们满足
binomial numbers because they satisfy
你能想到的每一个身份
every identity you could think of
所以这里是他们的公式R.
so here's their formula R of with
enfolds和我们在M维度，所以我们
enfolds and we're in M dimensions so we
相信早，我们的想法有
believe early and our thinking had m
等于2，但我们应该知道成长
equal to 2 but we should you know grow
起来让我们成为5维，所以我们
up and get em to be 5 dimensional so we
有一个5维让我们不要想
have a 5 dimensional let's not think
关于那个好，所以事实证明它是
about that ok so so it turns out it's
二项式数和0＆1up2和Mso
binomial numbers and 0 & 1 up 2 and M so
所以对于m等于2这是我的照片
so for m equal to 2 which is my picture
它结束了0加N1加n2和
it's ends and 0 plus N 1 plus n 2 and
和和是什么这那是什么成
and and what are these what is that into
意思是例如那是什么
mean for example what's that that's a
二项式数我不知道你是不是
binomial number I don't know if you're
一些人热衷于二项式数字
keen on binomial numbers some people
他们的一生都是二项式的
their whole lives go into binomial
数字所以它就像是它
numbers so so it's something like is it
它是因子除以n减2
is it n factorial divided by n minus 2
factorial+2factorial我认为是
factorial + 2 factorial I think that's
什么是数字意味着这就是
what that number means that's the
二项式数，所以这就是我上去
binomial number so this would be I go up
在这一点上，我希望得到
to so at this point I'm hoping to get
答案7我想我现在就说
the answer 7 I think right now I've put
在我已经达到了我的意思
in I've gone up to am equal to I mean
艾美认为我已经走了-所以我
Emmy put that I've gone up to - so I've
是的所以我觉得我很明显
yeah so I think yeah I've obviously
允许3个3削减和他们是当
allowed for 3 3 cuts and they are when
我们只有3是7，所以就是这样
we had just 3 was 7 so is that
是这样所以现在我正在接受他们
is this so so this is now I'm taking em
到b3，我希望答案是希望
to b3 and I'm hoping for hope answer is
七，所以什么是3什么是3所以我补充说
seven so what is 3 what is 3 so I add
这三件事就是二项式
these 3 things so what is 3 the binomial
2号被遗忘怎么说
number 3 with 2 forgotten how to say
我很惭愧地承认3选2
that I'm ashamed to admit 3 choose 2
谢谢
thanks
我知道有一个好方法，所以3是什么
I knew there was a good way so what is 3
选择2好把它放在3和2它在
choose 2 well put it in 3 and 2 it's in
已经
there already
所以这将超过1倍2
so it would be 6 over 1 times 2 this
将是3将是3和什么是3
would be 3 would that be 3 and what is 3
选择1你怎么知道你
choose 1 how do you know that you
可能是对mm-hm
probably right mm-hm
3我想是的哦，是的，可能是一个
3 I think yeah oh yeah probably a
定理，如果这些加到3
theorem that that if these add to 3
是的，所以我正在做N等于3
yeah so so this I'm doing N equals 3
好的，所以我们是的，我同意这是3和
okay so we yeah I agree that's 3 and
那么n到0
what about n to 0
什么是你必须忍受0
what's that you have to live with 0
因子不是0因子
factorial by 0 factorial is by no means
0什么是0因子1是的我
0 what so what is 0 factorial 1 yeah I
记得当我是本科生的时候
remember when I was an undergraduate
我赢了赌注或数学，但他没有
having a bet or math I won but he didn't
还清，所以是的，所以3这是3
pay off so yeah so so 3 this is 3
阶乘超过3阶乘以零
factorial over 3 factorial times zero
战士所以6次超过6次1
fighters so it's 6 over 6 times 1 so
不是一个是啊所以1比3和3比赛7
isn't one yeah so 1 in 3 and 3 makes 7
所以它证明了他们的公式
so it proves their formula
干得好，证明了公式但是
well done quite proved the formula but
他们通过归纳证明这一点的方式
their way to prove it is by an induction
如果你喜欢这个，我会的
and I'll just if you like this this
东西
stuff the
您使用归纳的递归
the recursion that you use induction on
这就是我们现在所做的事情
which is just what we did now what we
在这里做这里在四个号码进来
did here here comes in at number four
它切断了哦耶，然后我们
and it cuts through oh yeah and then we
只计算那里的四件
just counted the the four pieces there
所以是的他们让我告诉你
so yeah so they let me just tell you
他们是N和M的数字
what they are of N and M the number
我们正在寻找的是我们的号码
we're looking for is the number that we
有一个减少一个，所以这是
had with one less cut so that's the
以前的扁平件数加上
previous count of flat pieces plus the
数加那是数
number of the plus the number that was
这里是为作品的数量
here was for the number of pieces that
削减那个，这是我们的n减1米
cut that and that's our of n minus 1 M
减去1是的，是的，我不会去
minus 1 yeah and yeah I won't go go
更进一步，但这就是那个
further times up but this the and that
递归规则在in中被证明
rule for recursion is proved in the in
第7.1节摘自论文
the section 7.1 taken from the paper by
克莱因伯格和其他人是的，我想是的
Kleinberg and others yeah so ok I think
这是我不知道你的感受
this is I don't know what you feel this
对我来说这就像给了我一个更好的
for me this like gave me a better
觉得我明白了什么
feeling that I was understanding what
我们在这里有这样的功能
kind of functions we had here and so
然后问题是与这个家庭
then the question is to with this family
我们想要选择两个功能我们
of functions we want to choose two we
想要选择A和权重
want to choose the A's and the weights
A公司和B的给予匹配
the A's and the B's to give to to match
培训数据，以便我们有一个
the training data and so that we have a
在最小化总亏损问题
problem in in minimizing the total loss
我们有一个梯度下降
and we have a we have a gradient descent
问题所以我们必须找到梯度
problem so we have to find the gradient
所以这是周三的工作星期三工作
so that's Wednesdays job Wednesdays job
是找到F的梯度
is to find the gradient of F
好吧，那反向传播很好
okay and that's backpropagation good
thank you very much that's that's 7.1 is
非常感谢那就是7.1
DONE
done